Guide to the Roy Vernon Sowers Papers, 1920-1984
Department of Special Collections
Roy Vernon Sowers Papers,
1920-1984
Special Collections M0887
Sowers, Roy Vernon, 1897-
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of the estate of Margaret Cosgrave Sowers, 1996.
Scope and Content
Biographical information, correspondence, George Cosgrave correspondence, exhibit announcements, printing ephemera, and an incomplete set of his catalogs, #1-79.
Access Terms
Antin, Charles.; Bender, Albert.; Brasch, Frederick E. (Frederick Edward), 1875-1967.; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Cosgrave, George.; Edmunds, Will H.; Evans, Herbert.; Gentry, Helen.; Gunst, Morgan A.; Mason, Roger Burford.; Nash, John Henry.; Powell, Lawrence Clark.; Ritchie, Ward.; Sarton, George, 1884-1956.; Schad, Jasper.; Singer, Charles.; Sowers, Margaret Cosgrave.; Wilson, Adrian.; Wood, Casey A. (Casey Albert), 1856-1942.; Zeitlin, Jake.; Grabhorn Press.; John Howell Books.; Taylor & Taylor.; Book collecting.; Booksellers and bookselling--History--California.; Printing--California.; Printers. lcsh
Container List
- RVS biographical information 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jake Zeitlin biographical information 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- RVS correspondence with publishers and dealers 1920-30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- RVS correspondence 1930-60 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- RVS correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
- RVS correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
- RVS correspondence with Edmunds (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, George Cosgrave with booksellers 1920-30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- RVS exhibit announcements (Box 1, Folder 9)
- RVS business ephemera (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Printing ephemera (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Printing ephemera (Box 1, Folder 12)
Related Material
The Roy Vernon Sowers and Margaret Cosgrave Sowers papers, 1629-1994 M0888